（洛杉矶 公元2029年）
那些机器从核爆废墟中崛起
它们灭绝人类的战争 已经肆虐了数十年
但是决战不会在未来开打
它即将发生在这里 现在
今晚…
《终结者》
（洛杉矶 1984年 凌晨1点52分
怎么回事？该死的…
What the hell? Goddamn son-of-a-bitch…
怎么回事？
What the hell?
嘿 该我了
Hey, my turn.
嘿 这人搞什么鬼？
Hey, what's wrong with this picture?
夜色中漫步很惬意吗？
Nice night for a walk?
夜色中漫步很惬意
Nice night for a walk.
明天要洗衣服 没干净衣裳穿了？
Wash day tomorrow. Nothing clean, right?
对 没有干净衣裳穿了
Nothing clean. Right.
这家伙看来是喝高了
I think this guy's a couple of cans short of a six-pack.
把你的衣服给我 马上
Your clothes, give them to me. Now.
去你的 混蛋
Fuck you, asshole.
嘿 伙计 刚才看到那道亮光了吗？
Hey, buddy, did you just see a real bright light?
看到那家伙了吗？
See that guy?
站那儿别动
Hold it right there.
- 他要跑 - 嘿！我说了站住！
- He's rabbiting. - Hey! I said hold it!
走！
Go!
那混蛋的抢了我的裤子
That son-of-a-bitch took my pants.
- 今天是几号？日期 - 5月12日
- What day is it? The date. - 12th May.
- 星期四 - 哪年？
- Thursday. - What year?
他抢了我的枪 快追
He's got my gun. Let's go.
（照相）
（提供关爱和保护）
（莎拉·康纳）
替我看着点 大块头
Guard it for me, Big Buns.
嘿 我迟到了
Hi. I'm late.
我也是
So am I.
（莎拉·康纳）
- 我开工了 - 我也是
- I'm in it. - So am I.
- 麻烦你拿咖啡给我好吗？ - 好的
- Honey, can I have that coffee now? - Yes, sir.
- 谁要的牛排？ - 我要的是烤牛肉
- OK. Who gets the burly-beef? - I ordered barbecued.
我想是我的 可我没要炸薯条
I think that's mine, but I didn't order fries.
- 我要的是辣牛肉 - 好了 是谁点的牛排？
- Mine's the chili beef deluxe. - OK, who gets the burly-beef?
- 小姐 我们准备好点菜了 - 是 夫人
- Miss, we're ready to order now. - Yes, ma'am.
太对不起了
I'm so sorry.
这不是真皮吧？
This isn't real leather, is it?
孩子 干得好 我该把小费给你
Nice going, kid. I ought to give you the tip.
要这样想 一百年之后谁还在乎？
Look at it this way. In 100 years, who's gonna care?
（体育用品店）
那支12口径的自动步枪
The 12-gauge auto-loader.
意大利的 可以选手动或自动
That's Italian. You can go pump or auto.
0.45英寸口径 配备激光瞄准镜
The.45 long slide with laser sighting.
是新产品 刚进的货 是把好枪
These are new. We just got them in. That's a good gun.
轻扣扳机 打出激光
Just touch the trigger, the beam comes on,
将红点对准目标就行
and you put the red dot where you want the bullet to go.
百发百中
You can't miss.
- 还要别的吗？ - 40瓦等离子步枪
- Anything else? - Plasma rifle in the 40-watt range.
就是你看的 伙计
Hey, just what you see, pal.
那支乌兹9毫米的
The Uzi nine millimeter.
看来你很在行
You know your weapons, buddy.
任何一支都适合家庭防卫
Any one of these is ideal for home defense.
你打算要哪支？
So which will it be?
- 都要 - 我今天可以提前下班了
- All. - I may close early today.
你要的手枪得等15天 步枪嘛 现在就可以拿
It's a 15-day wait on the handguns, but the rifles you can take now.
- 你不能这样 - 错
- You can't do that. - Wrong.
嘿 宝贝 是的 是我
Hi, baby. Yeah, yeah, it's me.
听着 我要你过来接我 我的自行车坏了
Listen, I need you to come pick me up. My bike just broke down.
我不管你在干什么 过来接我 干嘛？
I don't care what you're doing. Come and get me. What the…
嘿 伙计 你的态度很成问题
Hey, man, you got a serious attitude problem.
- 莎拉·康纳？ - 是的
- Sarah Connor? - Yes?
我在休息 查克 卡拉在替我
I'm on my break, Chuck. Carla's got my station.
莎拉 过来 这事和你有关
Sarah, come here. It's about you. I mean, sort of.
太不可思议了 你无法相信 坐下 你会喜欢这个
So incredible. You're not gonna believe this. Sit, you're going to love this.
- 什么？ - …根据目击证人所说
- What? - …compiled from several witnesses.
一位叫莎拉·康纳 35岁 两个孩子的母亲
Once again, Sarah Connor, 35, mother of two,
今天下午在家里中弹身亡
brutally shot to death in her home this afternoon.
你死了 宝贝
You're dead, honey.
…如果你想购买音响
…if you're into sound,
那就来赛普尔韦达2500号 鲍勃立体声音响器材店
for the greatest sound around, come to Bob's Stereo at 2500 Sepulveda.
我们有低音和高音扩音器 最新的唱片
We've got woofers, tweeters, the newest in audio and compact discs.
还有图表均衡器和音响平衡器…
We've got graphic equalizers and sound balancers that…
抱歉
Sorry.
你好
Hello?
首先 我会一个个地解开你衬衣上的纽扣
First I'm gonna rip the buttons off your blouse one by one,
然后用舌头从你的脖颈开始 慢慢亲你
then run my tongue down your neck to your bare, gleaming breasts.
然后慢慢地…一点一点地脱掉你的裤子
And then slowly… slowly pull your jeans off inch by inch.
金珍 是文迪的电话
Ginger, it's Matt.
然后绕着圈地舔你的肚皮 一点一点地往下
And lick your belly in circles further and further down,
然后用我的牙齿脱掉你的内裤
and then pull your panties off with my teeth.
你是谁？
Who is this?
上帝 莎拉？
God. Sarah?
我的天 对不起
Jesus. I'm sorry.
我还以为你是… 能让金珍接电话吗？
I thought you were… Can I talk to Ginger, please?
当然
Sure.
是那个变态鬼
It's the creep.
喂？
Hello?
首先 我会一个个地解开你衬衣上的纽扣
First I'll rip the buttons off your blouse one by one…
你们这些该死的！我们走着瞧 放开我！
You fucking pigs! Wait till I get my hands on you. Get off me!
艾特
Ed.
- 什么事？ - 一名女死者
- What have you got? - Dead girl.
- 这我知道 - 莎拉·康纳 秘书 35岁
- I can see that. - Sarah Ann Connor, secretary, 35.
身中六枪 大口径武器
Shot six times at less than ten feet. Large caliber weapon.
你知道 我戴了眼镜
You know, these work.
- 这是什么？ - 第二名女死者
- What's this? - Dead girl two.
今天下午山谷分局送过来的
Sent over from the Valley division this afternoon.
你肯定这些命案是有动机的吗？
Are you sure there's a point to all of this?
你看死者的名字
Look at the name, Ed.
莎拉·康纳 没错吧？
Sarah Louise Connor. Is this right?
开玩笑
You're kidding me.
报纸会就此大做文章的
The press is gonna be short-stroking it.
- 一个特定模式的凶手 - 我讨厌古怪的案子
- A one-day pattern killer. - I hate the weird ones.
这样…
So…
不是一般的人能配得上的
Better than mortal man deserves.
（小心狗）
- 金珍 看到宝斯利了吗？ - 最近没有 你听留言了吗？
- Ginger, have you seen Pugsley? - Not lately. Did you check messages?
我以为你听了
I thought you did.
- 嘿 莎拉 我是妈妈 - 原来你在这儿
- Hi, Sarah, this is your mom… - There you are, young man.
你想想你妈吧
You mind your mother.
你好 莎拉 史丹·莫斯基出了点事儿
Hi, Sarah. Stan Morsky. Something's come up.
看来今天晚上我无法赴约了 实在脱不了身
Looks like I won't be able to make it tonight. Just can't get out of it.
真的很抱歉 我会下次弥补 改天打电话给你 再见
I'm really sorry. I'll make it up to you. Call you in a day or so. Bye.
那个混蛋 开辆保时捷又能怎么样？
That bum. So what if he has a Porsche?
他不能这样对你 这可是周五晚上
He can't treat you like this. It's Friday night, for Christ's sake.
我没事儿
I'll live.
我打碎他的膝盖
I'll break his kneecaps.
宝斯利依然爱我 是不是 宝贝？
Well, Pugsley still loves me. Don't you, baby?
天哪 真令人恶心
God. It's disgusting.
我去看电影 祝你玩儿得开心
I'm gonna go to a movie, kiddo. Have a good time.
- 我们会的 也祝你开心 - 好
- We will. You, too. - OK.
混蛋 文迪
Damn it, Matt.
- 哦 该死 - 警督！
- Oh, shit. - Lieutenant!
这些命案是根据电话簿姓名的排列次序发生的
These killings occurred in the order of their listings in the phone book.
- 我能告诉你什么？无可奉告 - 但是 警督…
- What can I tell you? No comment. - But, Lieutenant…
那杯咖啡已经凉了
That coffee's two hours cold.
我曾用它淹灭过一根香烟
I put a cigarette out in it.
- 你联系上下一个女的了吗？ - 没有 她的电话始终是留言
- Did you reach the next girl yet? - No. I got her answering machine.
- 派个小组过去 - 我派了一个小组 还没回音
- Send a unit. - I sent a unit. There's no answer.
- 公寓老板不在 - 给她打电话
- The apartment manager's not in. - Call her.
- 刚打过 - 再打
- I just called her. - Call her again.
给我根烟
Give me a cigarette.
你好 跟你开玩笑了 你在和机器说话
Hi, there. Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但也别害躁 没事儿 机器也需要爱 跟它聊聊吧
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too, so talk to it…
同样的回答
Same shit.
就管他叫该死的电话簿杀手吧
I can hear it now. He's gonna be called the goddamn Phone Book Killer.
我讨厌这些报界关注的案子 特别是这些古怪的案件
I hate these press cases. Especially the weird press cases.
- 你去哪儿？ - 去发表个声明
- Where are you going? - To make a statement.
或许让这帮走狗帮我们一个忙
Maybe make these jackals work for us for a change.
如果我能上11点的电视 或许她会打电话给我们
If I can get on the tube by 11:00, maybe she'll call us.
我的样子怎么样？
Well, how do I look?
- 很难看 头儿 - 去你的
- Like shit, boss. - Your mama.
刚刚收到的新闻 警方宣布了
This just in. Police have announced the name of the victim
今天发生的第二名遇害者的姓名
in the second of two execution style murders which took place today.
令人难以置信的是 两名遇害者都是同名同姓
Incredibly, the names of the two victims are virtually identical.
两个小时前35岁的莎拉·康纳 被发现死在…
Two hours ago, 35-year-old Sarah Ann Connor was pronounced dead…
- 能换个台吗？ - 莎拉·康纳…
- Can we change this? - Sarah Louise Connor…
别动！
Don't touch it!
警方拒绝猜测两宗案件的相似之处
Police are refusing to speculate on the similarity between the shooting deaths
现在没有发现两名被害人的关系
and no other connection between the two victims has been established yet.
我们将随时为大家报道该事件的最新进展
We'll have more on this late-breaking story as it comes in.
（黑科技酒吧）
- 嘿 这儿有电话吗？ - 在后面
- Hey, you got a phone? - It's in the back.
四块五毛
Hey, $4.50.
你已经接通了洛杉矶警局的紧急热线
You have reached the Los Angeles Police Department emergency number.
所有线路繁忙 如果需要警车支援 请稍候
All lines are busy. If you need a police car sent out to you, stay on the line.
宝斯利！
Pugsley! Shoo!
走开 我非把你做成皮带不可
Go on. I'm gonna make a belt out of you.
别逼我揍你 伙计
Don't make me bust you up, man.
你好 跟你开玩笑了 你在和机器说话
Hi, there. Fooled you. You're talking to a machine.
但也别害躁 没事儿 机器也需要爱
But don't be shy. It's OK. Machines need love, too.
跟它聊聊吧 金珍 也就是我 或者是莎拉 会给你回电话的
So talk to it and Ginger, that's me, or Sarah will get back to you.
听到嘟音后…
Wait for the beep.
金珍 我是莎拉 你在的话 把话筒拿起来
Ginger, this is Sarah. Pick up if you're there.
我在比科大道黑科技酒吧 我很害怕
I'm at this place on Pico Boulevard called Tech Noir. I'm really scared.
有人在跟踪我 希望你快点听这个留言
I think that there's somebody after me. I hope that you play this back soon.
我需要你和文迪尽快来接我
I need you and Matt to come and pick me up as soon as possible.
警方把我的电话转来转去 我会再和他们联系
The police keep transferring me around. I'm gonna give 'em another try.
我这里的电话是555-9175
The number here is 555-9175.
打电话给我 我需要你的帮助
Call me, kiddo. I need your help.
是她
It's her.
莎拉·康纳？我是特拉克斯勒警督
Sarah Connor? It's Lieutenant Traxler.
警督 别让我等了 别把我转到其它的部门
Lieutenant, don't put me on hold and don't transfer me to another department.
不用担心 不会的 别紧张 能告诉我你在哪儿吗？
Don't worry, I won't. Just relax. Can you tell me where you are?
- 一个叫黑科技的酒吧 - 我知道 在比科大道
- I'm in this bar called Tech Noir. - Yeah, I know it. It's on Pico.
- 你没事吧？ - 是的 但我不想离开
- Are you all right? - Yeah, but I don't wanna leave.
- 我觉得有人在跟踪我 - 注意听好了
- I think there's a guy following me. - Now, listen carefully.
你处在公共场所 你是安全的 我们会尽快过去
You're in a public place so you'll be safe till we get there.
呆在原地 别出去 也别去厕所
But stay visible. Don't go outside or even to the restroom.
- 我会很快派一辆车过去 - 好吧
- I'll have a car there in a minute. - OK.
嘿 那家伙没付钱
Hey, that guy didn't pay.
跟我走 如果你想活命的话
Come with me if you wanna live.
走呀！
Come on!
我是1-L-19 这里出现一宗肇事逃逸
This is one-L-19. I got a hit-and-run felony.
嫌疑人驾驶一辆灰色福特 沿第七街向西逃逸
Suspect vehicle: late model gray Ford headed westbound on Seventh.
他开得很快
He's really moving, punching lights all the way.
马上派辆救护车到第七街和百老汇街的交汇处
I'm gonna need an ambulance at Seventh and Broadway right now.
站着别动！
Hold it!
坐稳了
Hold on.
你受伤了吗？中弹了吗？
Are you injured? Are you shot?
照我说的做
Do exactly what I say. Exactly.
你不许动 不能出声
Don't move unless I say. Don't make a sound unless I say.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
- 明白吗？ - 是的！求你别伤害我
- Do you understand? - Yes! Please don't hurt me.
我来这儿是为了帮你
I'm here to help you.
我是里斯 科技部队的中士 DN38416号 受命前来保护你
I'm Reese. Sergeant Tech-Com. DN38416. Assigned to protect you.
你是被刺杀的目标
You've been targeted for termination.
我是1-L-19 沿奥林匹克街向西行驶 快到奥弗兰了
This is one-L-19. Westbound on Olympic, approaching Overland.
一定是搞错了 我没做任何事
This is a mistake. I didn't do anything.
现在没有 可你将来会 保护你的生命很重要
No, but you will. It's very important that you live.
这不是真的 那个人怎么还能站起来追你…
This isn't true. How could that man just get up after you…
那不是人 是机器
It's not a man. A machine.
是终结者 生化人系统101型号
A Terminator. Cyberdyne Systems model 101.
机器？像机器人？
A machine? Like a robot?
不是机器人 生化人 电脑控制的有机体
Not a robot. A cyborg. Cybernetic organism.
- 不 他刚才在流血 - 等一下
- No. He was bleeding. - Just a second.
把头低下！
Get your head down!
好了 听着
All right, listen.
终结者是一个混合物 半人半机械
The Terminator's an infiltration unit. Part man, part machine.
里面是一个超级合金战斗骨架 受微处理器控制
Underneath it's a hyper-alloy combat chassis. Microprocessor controlled.
全副武装 结实强悍 但外表是人的体貌特征
Fully armored, very tough. But outside it's living human tissue.
肌肉 皮肤 头发 血液… 都是围绕着机械生长的
Flesh, skin, hair, blood… grown for the cyborgs.
- 听着 里斯 我不知道 - 注意
- Look, Reese, I don't know… - Pay attention.
我得把这部车扔掉
I gotta ditch this car.
600系列的是橡胶皮肤 很容易识别
The 600-Series had rubber skin. We spotted them easy.
但这些是新的 它们很像人类
But these are new. They look human.
流汗 口臭 诸如此类 很难辨别
Sweat, bad breath, everything. Very hard to spot.
只有等他向你下手的时候 才能消灭他
I had to wait till he moved on you before I could zero him.
听着 我不傻 他们不可能制造那种东西
Look, I am not stupid. They cannot make things like that yet.
现在不能 40年内也不可能
Not yet. Not for about 40 years.
你是说它来自未来？
Are you saying it's from the future?
一种可能出现的未来
One possible future.
你觉得我对科技一窍不通
From your point of view, I don't know tech stuff.
这么说你也是来自未来 对吗？
Then you're from the future, too. Is that right?
- 没错 - 没错
- Right. - Right.
机器人没有痛感 我有 别再这样做
Cyborgs don't feel pain. I do. Don't do that again.
- 让我走 - 听着 你要明白
- Just let me go. - Listen and understand.
那个终结者就在外面
That Terminator is out there.
它是不讲情面 不讲道理的
It can't be bargained with, it can't be reasoned with.
它没有同情心 没有自责 没有恐惧
It doesn't feel pity or remorse or fear
它绝不会放下屠刀 除非你死掉
and it absolutely will not stop, ever, until you are dead.
你能制止它吗？
Can you stop it?
不知道
I don't know.
靠这些武器 我不知道
With these weapons, I don't know.
各小组注意 在一个停车场内发现可疑的灰色福特…
All units. Ford suspect vehicle has been found in a parking structure…
里斯 为什么是我？
Reese, why me?
为什么它想要我的命？
Why does it want me?
曾经发生了一场核战争
There was a nuclear war.
未来数年后…
A few years from now…
…这里的一切 这个地方 所有的东西…
…all this, this whole place, everything…
…都将不复存在
…it's gone. Just gone.
有一些生还者
There were survivors.
散落各地
Here, there.
没人知道是谁发动的战争
Nobody even knew who started it.
- 是那些机器 莎拉 - 我不明白
- It was the machines, Sarah. - I don't understand.
防卫网络计算机
Defense network computers.
新型的 功能强大…
New, powerful…
…连接到了所有的东西上 被委以重任操控一切
…hooked into everything, trusted to run it all.
他们说它变得聪明起来… 一种智能的新秩序
They say it got smart… a new order of intelligence.
之后它视人类为威胁 和那边的人不一样
Then it saw all people as a threat. Not just the ones on the other side.
它在刹那间决定了我们的命运
It decided our fate in a microsecond.
消灭
Extermination.
你目睹了这场战争？
Did you see this war?
不 我在战后长大 在废墟里
No. I grew up after. In the ruins.
忍饥挨饿 躲避那些H-K
Starving. Hiding from the H-Ks.
- H-K ？ - 捕猎杀手
- H-Ks? - Hunter-killers.
机械制造厂生产的巡逻机器
Patrol machines built in automated factories.
我们大部分人被抓了起来 关在集中营等着被逐一消灭
Most of us were rounded up, put in camps for orderly disposal.
这是被激光扫描器烙下的
This was burned in by laser scanner.
我们中的一部分人得以活下来 负责…
Some of us were kept alive. To work.
…搬运尸体
Loading bodies.
处理尸体的部门昼夜运转
The disposal units ran night and day.
我们差一点就没命了
We were that close to going out forever.
不过 有一个人教我们反抗
But there was one man who taught us to fight.
攻击了集中营的网线
To storm the wire of the camps.
把那些金属混蛋砸个稀巴烂
To smash those metal motherfuckers into junk.
他扭转了局势 带领我们脱离了险境
He turned it around. He brought us back from the brink.
他姓康纳 叫约翰·康纳
His name was Connor. John Connor.
你的儿子 你未出生的儿子
Your son, Sarah. Your unborn son.
开车！
Drive!
里斯！
Reese!
不 里斯 他们会杀你的
No, Reese. No, no, no. They'll kill you.
坐在凯迪拉克上的人 把手举起来
You in the Cadillac, let me see your hands now.
下车
Get out of the car.
跪下
Drop to your knees.
- 下车 - 跪下
- Out of the car. - Drop to the ground.
莎拉 喝点水吧
Sarah. Sarah, try to drink some of this.
听着 你肯定是他们？
Listen, are you sure it's them?
我是说 也许我应该看一看尸体
I mean, maybe I should look at the bodies.
他们的身份已经证实 没有问题
No. They've been identified and there's no doubt.
金珍
Ginger.
- 老姐 - 莎拉
- Kiddo. - Sarah…
- 莎拉 这位是萧伯文医生 - 你好莎拉
- Sarah, this is Dr. Silberman. - Hi, Sarah.
告诉他里斯对你说的一切 你能应付得了吗？
I want you to tell him everything Reese told you. Do you feel up to that?
是的 我想可以
Yeah, I guess so.
- 你是医生吗？ - 犯罪心理学医生
- You're a doctor? - Criminal psychologist.
- 里斯是疯了吗？ - 我们就是要查证一下
- Is Reese crazy? - That's what we're gonna find out.
这么说你是军人 是在为谁打仗？
So you're a soldier. Fighting for whom?
2021至2027年在132团服役 指挥官是贝里
With the 132nd under Perry. From '21 to '27.
今年是2027年？
That's the year 2027?
对 之后我被分配到…
That's right. Then I was assigned…
- 太有意思了 - …约翰·康纳的部队
- This is fucking great. - …under John Connor.
- 敌人是谁？ - 一个计算机防卫系统…
- Who was the enemy? - A computer defense system built…
该死 抱歉
Goddamn. Sorry.
…由生化人系统制造的
…built for SAC-NORAD by Cyberdyne Systems.
是这样
I see.
这个计算机认为 杀掉敌人的母亲 就能赢得战争的胜利
And this computer thinks it can win by killing the mother of its enemy.
杀了他 在他孕育之前
Killing him, in effect, before he's even conceived.
算是一种追溯堕胎？
A sort of retroactive abortion?
萧伯文让我笑死了 上周有个家伙烧了他的羊皮袄
Silberman cracks me up. Last week, a guy burned his Afghan.
- 开始他的心情很不好… - 艾特 闭嘴
- He screwed it first… - Ed, shut up.
那台计算机为什么不直接杀了康纳？
Why didn't the computer just kill Connor then?
为什么要有这个终结者的计划？
Why this elaborate scheme with the Terminator?
它别无选择 他们的防卫网络被摧毁了
It had no choice. Their defense grid was smashed.
我们赢了 就是没有康纳 也不会有任何区别
We'd won. Taking out Connor then would make no difference.
天网必需铲除它的整个组织
Skynet had to wipe out his entire existence.
是不是当你们控制了实验室 找到了…叫什么来着？
Is that when you captured the lab complex and found… What is it called?
时空转移装置？
The time displacement equipment?
不错 终结者已经穿越过来了
That's right. The Terminator had already gone through.
康纳派我来拦截 他们把整个地方都炸毁了
Connor sent me to intercept and they blew the whole place.
那你准备怎么回去呢？
Well, how are you supposed to get back?
我回不去了
I can't.
没有人能回家 也没有人可以过来
Nobody goes home. Nobody else comes through.
这里只有他和我
It's just him and me.
你为什么没有带武器？一些更先进的东西
Why didn't you bring any weapons? Something more advanced.
你们没有激光枪吗？
Don't you have ray guns?
- 激光枪 - 给我看看一件未来的科技
- Ray guns. - Show me a piece of future technology.
你光着身子过来 和生物有机体驱动磁场有关
You go naked. Something about the field generated by a living organism.
- 没生命的东西是过不来的 - 为什么？
- Nothing dead will go. - Why?
这鬼东西又不是我造的
I didn't build the fucking thing.
好 好 但这个电子人如果是金属的…
OK, OK. But this cyborg, if it's metal…
- 被生命组织包裹着的 - 哦 没错
- Surrounded by living tissue. - Oh, right.
这材料多棒 我可以因他而功成名就
This is great stuff. I could make a career out of this guy.
看这个多聪明？不需要证据
See how clever it is? It doesn't require a shred of proof.
大部分偏执狂幻觉都很复杂 但这个却才华横溢
Most paranoid delusions are intricate, but this is brilliant.
- 为什么另外的两个女人被杀？ - 大部分档案在战争中遗失
- Why were the other two women killed? - Most records were lost in the war.
天网对康纳的母亲一无所知
Skynet knew almost nothing about Connor's mother.
她的全名 她的住址 他们只知道是哪座城市
Her full name, where she lived. They just knew the city.
那个终结者只是受程序控制
The Terminator was just being systematic.
- 我们再来谈谈… - 听着 我说的已经够多的了
- Let's go back… - Look, you have heard enough.
我已经回答了你们的问题 现在我要见莎拉·康纳
I have answered your questions, now I have to see Sarah Connor.
- 我恐怕不能做主 - 那我为什么要和你谈？
- I'm afraid that's not up to me. - Then why am I talking to you?
- 这里谁是负责人？ - 拜托…
- Who is in authority here? - Please…
闭嘴！
Shut up!
你们还是不明白 对吗？
You still don't get it, do you?
他会找到她 他就是要这样 他的目的就是这个
He'll find her. That's what he does. That's all he does.
你们无法阻止他
You can't stop him.
他会掐住她的喉咙 挖出她的心
He'll reach down her throat and pull her fucking heart out!
- 医生 - 放开我！
- Doc. - Let go of me!
对不起
Sorry.
这么说…里斯他疯了？
So Reese is crazy?
用专业术语讲 他是个疯子
In technical terminology, he's a loon.
莎拉 这是他们所说的防弹衣 我们的特种部队都穿这个
Sarah, this is what they call body armor. Our TAC guys wear these.
它能阻挡12口径的火力
It'll stop a 12-gauge round.
那个人一定是穿了这东西
This other individual must've been wearing one under his coat.
摸一摸 来呀
Feel that. Go ahead.
- 他打碎挡风玻璃又怎么解释 - 也许他吸食了麻醉剂
- He punched through the windshield. - He was probably on PCP.
几个小时内骨头断了 都不会有感觉
Broke every bone in his hand. He wouldn't feel it for hours.
曾经有过这样一个家伙… 你看到这个伤痕了吗？
There was this guy once… You see this scar?
- 拿着 - 谢谢
- Here. - Thank you.
隔壁房间有一个沙发 躺下睡一会儿吧
There's a couch in this other room. Stretch out and get some sleep.
你母亲从大熊镇赶到这儿 至少还有一个小时
Be at least an hour before your mother gets here from Big Bear.
- 我睡不着 - 试试吧
- I can't sleep. - Try.
看上去可能不怎么样 但那张沙发的确很舒服
It may not look it, but that couch is very comfortable.
你在这里绝对安全 楼里有30名警员
You'll be perfectly safe. We got 30 cops in this building.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
我是莎拉·康纳的朋友 我知道她在这儿 能让我见她吗？
I'm a friend of Sarah Connor. I was told she's here. Could I see her?
不行 她在录口供
No. Can't see her. She's making a statement.
她在哪儿？
Where is she?
这得需要一会儿 如果你愿意等 那边有凳子
It may take a while. If you wanna wait, there's a bench over there.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
- 是不是恐怖分子？ - 走 走！
- Are they terrorists? - Let's go, let's go!
呆在这儿
Stay here.
我们赶快离开这儿！
Let's get outta here!
（请勿靠近 小心）
看着他
Watch him.
艾特…
Ed…
嘿！
Hey!
莎拉！
Sarah!
里斯
Reese.
这边
This way.
新闻时间 4点36分
KFLB news time 4:36.
头条新闻：加州历史上最大规模的
Top story of the hour: the largest single law enforcement mobilization
执法行动正在展开
in California history is currently underway.
5个南部县区的警力全部投入到大搜捕…
Police in five counties are engaged in a massive manhunt for…
拿着这个
Take this.
我们把它从公路上推下去
All right, let's get this off the road.
- 你冷吗？ - 冻僵了
- You cold? - Freezing.
里斯？
Reese?
- 你的名是？ - 凯尔
- You got a first name? - Kyle.
凯尔 你穿越时空的时候 是什么感觉？
Kyle, what's it like when you go through time?
白光
White light.
痛苦
Pain.
- 或许就像出生时一样吧 - 哦 天哪！
- It's like being born maybe. - Oh, my God.
我刚才中了一枪
I caught one back there.
- 你是说你中弹了？ - 不太严重
- You mean you got shot? - It's not bad.
- 我们得赶快去找医生 - 没事 算了吧
- We gotta get you to a doctor. - It's OK. Forget it.
算了？你疯了吗？把衣服脱掉
What do you mean, forget it? Are you crazy? Take this off.
天哪
Jesus.
看到了？它穿过了皮肉
See? It passed right through the meat.
这让我作呕
This is gonna make me puke.
- 你能说些别的事吗？ - 说什么？
- Would you just talk about something? - What?
我不知道 随便说 说说我的儿子
I don't know. Anything. Just talk. Tell me about my son.
他和我一样高
He's about my height.
他的眼睛和你一样
He has your eyes.
他长得什么样？
What's he like?
你信任他 他有一种力量
You trust him. He's got a strength.
我愿意为约翰·康纳去死
I'd die for John Connor.
我现在至少知道 该给他取什么名字了
Well, at least now I know what to name him.
我想你不会知道他父亲是谁吧 好让我遇到他时不会让他滚开
Don't suppose you know who the father is so I won't tell him to get lost?
约翰很少谈到他
John never said much about him.
- 我知道他在战前就死了… - 等等
- I know he dies before the war… - Wait.
我不想知道
I don't wanna know.
是不是约翰派你来的？
So was it John that sent you here?
是我自愿的
I volunteered.
- 为什么？ - 这是一次认识传奇人物的机会
- Why? - It was a chance to meet the legend.
莎拉·康纳教育她的儿子奋斗 有条理
Sarah Connor, who taught her son to fight, organize,
时刻准备着 在他还小的时候
prepare from when he was a kid.
当你们在战前四处躲藏时
When you were in hiding before the war.
你用过去时说一些我还没有做的事
You're talking about things I haven't done yet in the past tense.
这让我感到荒唐
It's driving me crazy.
你肯定没有找错人？
Are you sure you have the right person?
我肯定
I'm sure.
我像那个未来的母亲吗？
Come on. Do I look like the mother of the future?
我坚强吗？有调理吗？我甚至无法做到收支平衡
I mean, am I tough? Organized? I can't even balance my checkbook.
我没有要求这个荣誉 我也不想要它
Look, Reese, I didn't ask for this honor and I don't want it.
绝对不要
Any of it.
你儿子要我告诉你 他要我把它背下来
Your son gave me a message to give to you. Made me memorize it.
“感谢你在黑暗年代的勇气
"Thank you, Sarah, for your courage through the dark years.
你即将面对的事 我帮不了你
I can't help you with what you must soon face,
只能说未来还没有尘埃落定
except to say the future is not set.
你一定要比想象中的自己更坚强
You must be stronger than you imagine you can be.
一定要活下去 否则我永远不会存在”
You must survive or I will never exist."
完了
That's all.
包扎得很好
It's a good field dressing.
你喜欢吗？
You like it?
这是我第一次
It's my first.
睡一会儿吧 天快亮了
Get some sleep. It'll be light soon.
好
OK.
再跟我谈一会
Talk to me some more.
谈什么？
About what?
告诉我你家在哪儿
Tell me about where you're from.
好吧
All right.
你白天藏起来 晚上可以出来活动
You stay down by day, but at night you can move around.
你仍然要小心谨慎 因为捕猎的杀手使用红外线
You still have to be careful because the H-Ks use infrared.
但它们没有那么聪明 约翰教我们对付它们的办法
But they're not too bright. John taught us ways to dust them.
就是当那些渗透者出现时
That's when the infiltrators started to appear.
终结者是最新型的
The Terminators were the newest.
最难对付的
The worst.
以搜索模式进入你的防区 你的位置以北750米处
Traversing your sector in search mode. 750 meters north of your position.
我们走
Let's go.
- 里斯 DN384… - 对 让他进来
- Reese. DN384… - Right. Let him in.
终结者！
Terminator!
我做梦梦到了狗
I was dreaming about dogs.
我们用狗来提防终结者
We use 'em to spot Terminators.
你的世界很可怕
Your world is pretty terrifying.
嘿 伙计 里面有一只死猫吗？
Hey, buddy, you got a dead cat in there or what?
（可能的回答）
（是/不是 或什么？ 走开 过一会再来）
（去你的 混蛋 去你的）
（去你的 混蛋）
去你的 混蛋
Fuck you, asshole.
（妈妈的小屋 大熊镇 云杉路181号）
该死的
God damn.
谢谢你
Thank you.
（迪基 汽车旅馆）
这个够吗？
Is this enough?
够了 我不想问你从哪弄来的
Yeah, it's enough. I don't wanna ask where you got it.
- 来了 - 我们要一个房间
- I'm coming. - We need a room.
- 好的 - 带厨房的
- All right. - With a kitchen.
有带厨房的吗？
Do you have one with a kitchen?
我很想洗个澡
I am dying for a shower.
还要检查一下你的绷带
We should check your bandage, too.
稍后 我要出去买东西
Later. I'm going out for supplies.
拿着这个
Keep this.
妈 我不能告诉你我在哪儿 有人告诉我不能说
No, I can't tell you where I am, Mom. I was told not to say.
但我要知道在哪儿能找到你
But I need to know where to reach you.
你告诉我躲在这间小屋中 却不告诉我发生了什么
You tell me to hide out at the cabin and you won't tell me what's going on?
我很担心
I am worried sick here.
好吧 这是电话号码
OK. OK, here's the number.
- 准备好了吗？ - 是的 说吧
- You ready? - Yes. Go ahead.
408-555-1439 九号房间
It's 408-555-1439. Room nine.
- 记住了？ - 记住了
- Got it? - I've got it.
我得走了 抱歉 现在不能讲得太多
I gotta go. I'm sorry I can't tell you more right now.
我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mom.
我也爱你 宝贝
I love you, too, sweetheart.
- 迪基汽车旅馆 - 告诉我你的地址
- Tiki Motel. - Give me your address there.
买了些什么？
What have we got?
（樟脑球）
樟脑球… 玉米糖浆… 氨水
Mothballs… corn syrup… ammonia.
晚饭吃什么？
What's for dinner?
- 塑料炸弹 - 听起来不错
- Plastique. - That sounds good.
这是什么？
What is it?
硝酸甘油基料 更稳定些的
It's a nitroglycerin base. It's a bit more stable.
我小的时候学会的
I learned to make it when I was a kid.
千万别弄到线上
Make sure there's none on the threads.
像这样
Like this.
把盖拧上
Screw the end cap on.
轻轻地
Very gently.
你的童年一定很好玩
You must've had a fun childhood.
很好
That's good.
好了 像这样再做六个 我来制作引信
All right. Six more like that and I'll get started on the fuses.
他会找到我们吗？
He'll find us, won't he?
也许
Probably.
这事永远都完不了 是吗？
It'll never be over, will it?
看看我 我在发抖
Look at me. I'm shaking.
好一个传奇人物 你肯定很失望
Some legend. You must be pretty disappointed.
不 我没失望
No, I'm not.
凯尔 你那个时代的女人
Kyle, the women in your time,
她们是什么样子？
what are they like?
优秀的战士
Good fighters.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
有没有意中人？
Was there someone special?
意中人？
Someone?
女孩子
A girl, you know.
没有
No.
从来没有
Never.
从来没有？
Never?
抱歉 我很抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
这么多的痛苦
So much pain.
痛苦是可控的 只要别去想它
Pain can be controlled. You just disconnect it.
那你就没有感觉吗？
So you feel nothing?
约翰·康纳曾把你的相片给过我
John Connor gave me a picture of you once.
当时我不明白原因
I didn't know why at the time.
那是张很旧的 褪了色的照片
It was very old, torn, faded.
你很年轻 就像现在这个样子 只是有些悲伤
You were young like you are now. You seemed just a little sad.
我一直在想 你当时在想什么
I used to always wonder what you were thinking at that moment.
我能记得每一根纹路…
I memorized every line…
…每一条曲线
…every curve.
我穿越时空是为了你 莎拉
I came across time for you, Sarah.
我爱你 一直爱着你
I love you. I always have.
我不该这样说
I shouldn't have said that.
快点儿想
Think fast.
交换位置
Trade places.
快点儿！开快点儿！
Faster! Drive faster!
凯尔！哦 天呐
Kyle! Oh, my God.
凯尔
Kyle.
狗娘养的！
Son-of-a-bitch!
你呆在这儿
You stay here.
我们赶快离开这儿
Let's get outta here.
下车
Get out.
凯尔 快 起来
Kyle. Come on. Get up.
凯尔 快
Kyle, come on.
帮帮我！出来 出来
Help me! Get out. Get out.
不要停 跑！
Don't stop. Run!
莎拉！
Sarah!
凯尔
Kyle.
凯尔 凯尔…
Kyle. Kyle…
我们成功了
We did it, Kyle. We got him.
不！
No!
等一下
Wait.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
掩护 这样他跟踪不到我们
Cover, so he can't track us.
（自动生产流程启动）
快！快点儿
Come on! Come on.
不 凯尔！快点儿！
No, Kyle! Come on!
- 快！ - 别管我
- Come on! - Leave me here.
快点儿 里斯！站起来 士兵
Move it, Reese! On your feet, soldier!
站起来！
On your feet!
走！
Move it!
到后面去
Get back. Go back.
- 跑 莎拉 - 不
- Run, Sarah. - No.
跑！
Run!
来吧 混蛋
Come on, motherfucker.
不
No.
（液压机启动）
你被终结了 该死的
You're terminated, fucker.
凯尔
Kyle.
第七盘 11月10日 我在哪儿？
Tape seven. November 10. Where was I?
最难决定的是应该告诉你什么
What's most difficult is trying to decide what to tell you and what not to.
但到你长大能明白磁带内容时 我还有时间
But I guess I have a while before you're old enough to understand these tapes.
目前来讲它们对我更重要 这样我可以把它说明白
They're more for me at this point just so that I can get it straight.
加满
Fill her up.
我是否该告诉你 关于你父亲的事？
Should I tell you about your father?
孩子 这可是个难题
Boy, that's a tough one.
如果知道他是你父亲 会影响你派他来此的决定吗？
Will it affect your decision to send him here, knowing that he is your father?
如果你不派凯尔来这里 那就不会有你了
If you don't send Kyle, you can never be.
天哪 整天想着这事 人都要发疯了
God, a person could go crazy thinking about this.
我相信我会告诉你的
I suppose I will tell you.
为了他 我必须这样
I owe him that.
也许它能有所帮助…
Maybe it'll help if…
…如果你知道在我们共处的那段时间…
…you know that in the few hours that we had together…
…我们相爱得无怨无悔
…we loved a lifetime's worth.
- 他在说什么？ - 他说你长得很漂亮
- What did he just say? - He says you're very beautiful.
他不好意思向你索要5美元的照相费
He is ashamed to ask you for five American dollars for this picture.
可是如果不向你索要 他爸爸就会揍他
But if he doesn't, his father will beat him.
真会做生意 孩子
Pretty good hustle, kid.
他刚才说什么？
What did he just say?
他说风暴就要来了
He said there's a storm coming in.
我知道
I know.